<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="4.2.1">Jekyll</generator><link href="http://localhost:4000/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="http://localhost:4000/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2022-01-26T00:23:39+01:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/feed.xml</id><title type="html">MaxDH.info</title><subtitle>Stay Enthusiastic</subtitle><author><name>Max Daiber-Huppert</name></author><entry><title type="html">Welcome to Jekyll!!!</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/jekyll/update/welcome-to-jekyll/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Welcome to Jekyll!!!" /><published>2022-01-02T19:30:15+01:00</published><updated>2022-01-02T19:30:15+01:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/jekyll/update/welcome-to-jekyll</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/jekyll/update/welcome-to-jekyll/"><![CDATA[<p>You’ll find this post in your <code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">_posts</code> directory. Go ahead and edit it and re-build the site to see your changes. You can rebuild the site in many different ways, but the most common way is to run <code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">jekyll serve</code>, which launches a web server and auto-regenerates your site when a file is updated.</p>

<p>Jekyll requires blog post files to be named according to the following format:</p>

<p><code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">YEAR-MONTH-DAY-title.MARKUP</code></p>

<p>Where <code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">YEAR</code> is a four-digit number, <code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">MONTH</code> and <code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">DAY</code> are both two-digit numbers, and <code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">MARKUP</code> is the file extension representing the format used in the file. After that, include the necessary front matter. Take a look at the source for this post to get an idea about how it works.</p>

<p>Jekyll also offers powerful support for code snippets:</p>

<figure class="highlight"><pre><code class="language-ruby" data-lang="ruby"><span class="k">def</span> <span class="nf">print_hi</span><span class="p">(</span><span class="nb">name</span><span class="p">)</span>
  <span class="nb">puts</span> <span class="s2">"Hi, </span><span class="si">#{</span><span class="nb">name</span><span class="si">}</span><span class="s2">"</span>
<span class="k">end</span>
<span class="n">print_hi</span><span class="p">(</span><span class="s1">'Tom'</span><span class="p">)</span>
<span class="c1">#=&gt; prints 'Hi, Tom' to STDOUT.</span></code></pre></figure>

<p>Check out the <a href="https://jekyllrb.com/docs/home">Jekyll docs</a> for more info on how to get the most out of Jekyll. File all bugs/feature requests at <a href="https://github.com/jekyll/jekyll">Jekyll’s GitHub repo</a>. If you have questions, you can ask them on <a href="https://talk.jekyllrb.com/">Jekyll Talk</a>.</p>]]></content><author><name>Max Daiber-Huppert</name></author><category term="jekyll" /><category term="update" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[You’ll find this post in your _posts directory. Go ahead and edit it and re-build the site to see your changes. You can rebuild the site in many different ways, but the most common way is to run jekyll serve, which launches a web server and auto-regenerates your site when a file is updated. Jekyll requires blog post files to be named according to the following format: YEAR-MONTH-DAY-title.MARKUP Where YEAR is a four-digit number, MONTH and DAY are both two-digit numbers, and MARKUP is the file extension representing the format used in the file. After that, include the necessary front matter. Take a look at the source for this post to get an idea about how it works. Jekyll also offers powerful support for code snippets: def print_hi(name) puts "Hi, #{name}" end print_hi('Tom') #=&gt; prints 'Hi, Tom' to STDOUT. Check out the Jekyll docs for more info on how to get the most out of Jekyll. File all bugs/feature requests at Jekyll’s GitHub repo. If you have questions, you can ask them on Jekyll Talk.]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Smart Wall</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/optics/qoto/smart-wall/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Smart Wall" /><published>2018-09-03T03:10:15+02:00</published><updated>2018-09-03T03:10:15+02:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/optics/qoto/smart-wall</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/optics/qoto/smart-wall/"><![CDATA[<p><em>You can find the original toot on <a href="https://qoto.org/@MaxDH/100658697754857026">qoto</a>.</em></p>

<p>I read about a new smart wall (glass) from NanaWall <a href="https://www.nanawall.com/products/whiteout">[1]</a>.</p>

<p>I was wondering how it worked. So far I only learned something about nematic liquid crystal displays (LCD). With the following cell configurations Fréedericksz cell, VA cell, twisted nematic LC cell (similar to the Fréedericksz cell).</p>

<p>I read a little in a book <a href="https://www.amazon.com/Liquid-Crystal-Displays-Addressing-Electro-Optical/dp/1119667917">[2]</a> about polymer dispersed LCDs (PDLCDs).
These displays can address states between a scatter mode, where the display looks like a opal glass panel, and a transparent mode. With a contrast ratio of approx. 40:1, compared to a newspaper with a contrast approx. 8:1.</p>

<p>That sounds very similar.</p>

<p>Some more information about PDLCDs:
The nematic liquid crystals are arranged as droplets in a polymer binder between two glass plates with electrodes.
These droplets have a random orientation and so the refractive index is random. This causes the light to be scattered at a wide angle to the observer (scattering mode).
By apply an electric field the molecules orient themselves parallel to the field. With the result that the refractive index is almost the same. This means that the light can not scatter through the display (transparent mode).</p>

<p>This type of display don’t require a polariser.
I think that’s a big advantage of this technology. This way don’t lose 50-60% of the light beam at the polariser. This enables us to achieve a high transmission rate.
In my opinion, one disadvantage is that we need an applied electrical field for the transparent mode. Because in this case I don’t want an opaque window at a power blackout.</p>

<p>This was just one possible technology. Wikipedia <a href="https://en.m.wikipedia.org/wiki/Smart_glass">[3]</a> lists these technologies: electrochromic, photochromic, thermochromic, suspended-particle and micro-blind and polymer-dispersed liquid-crystal devices.</p>

<p>Maybe you have another idea.</p>

<p>Now it’s time. Good night.</p>

<p><a href="https://www.nanawall.com/products/whiteout">[1]</a> https://www.nanawall.com/products/whiteout</p>

<p><a href="https://www.amazon.com/Liquid-Crystal-Displays-Addressing-Electro-Optical/dp/1119667917">[2]</a> Liquid Cristal Displays, Addressing Schemes and electro-optical effects, Ernst Lueder</p>

<p><a href="https://en.m.wikipedia.org/wiki/Smart_glass">[3]</a> https://en.m.wikipedia.org/wiki/Smart_glass</p>]]></content><author><name>Max Daiber-Huppert</name></author><category term="optics" /><category term="qoto" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[You can find the original toot on qoto.]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Magic Leap</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/optics/qoto/magic-leap/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Magic Leap" /><published>2018-08-30T21:50:15+02:00</published><updated>2018-08-30T21:50:15+02:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/optics/qoto/magic-leap</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/optics/qoto/magic-leap/"><![CDATA[<p><em>You can find the original toot on <a href="https://qoto.org/@MaxDH/100640451319364854">[1]</a>.</em></p>

<p>“Can you share some of your thoughts on #photonics as it relates to spacial computing (i.e. Magic Leap)?”<a href="https://qoto.org/@absolutus/100634867961132450">[2]</a></p>

<p>My first thought was, how does the display work?</p>

<p>I found a patent from Magic Leap, Inc.
Maybe the Magic Leap One works like this =)</p>

<p>In order to obtain a real 3D image, it is necessary to create a light field as if from a real object.
This can be done by modulating the wave field, e.g. as a sphere, Fig. 2A<a href="https://patents.google.com/patent/US20140003762">[3]</a>. 
When we “see” such a spherical light field, it looks as if it comes from a (virtual) point source.</p>

<p>The patent describes the stacking of the light-guid optical elements to a 3D display (WRAP), see Fig. 5A<a href="https://patents.google.com/patent/US20140003762">[3]</a>.</p>

<p>By using a beam deflector, any 3D pixel can be addressed. The result is that the calculated virtual environment can be projected into the wearer’s eyes.</p>

<p>Some interesting points of the patent</p>
<ul>
  <li>Section 0034: limited number of slices of a 3D volume (“…less than 16 to 36 or more…”)</li>
  <li>Section 0036: How is the light field generated?</li>
  <li>Section 0048 ff: WRAP device</li>
  <li>Section 0052 ff.: How the WRAP works (in particular section 0055f)</li>
</ul>

<p>Please correct me if I’m wrong.</p>

<p><a href="https://qoto.org/@absolutus/100634867961132450">[1]</a> https://qoto.org/@absolutus/100634867961132450</p>

<p><a href="https://qoto.org/@MaxDH/100640451319364854">[2]</a>: https://qoto.org/@MaxDH/100640451319364854</p>

<p><a href="https://patents.google.com/patent/US20140003762">[3]</a> https://patents.google.com/patent/US20140003762</p>]]></content><author><name>Max Daiber-Huppert</name></author><category term="optics" /><category term="qoto" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[You can find the original toot on [1].]]></summary></entry></feed>